quick disclosure
okay sorry quick disclosure I mean I
have not put it on the slide anything
but I do own this talk for the last I
think two years now more than two years
not made money but still still hoping
that someday it will turn around so
quick overview on The General Insurance
sector
so I'm in the market the numbers are all
there on the screen so there's no point
me repeating it but if we just look at
the sort of market share gains for the
private insurers as a whole
and the growth they have seen over the
last 10 years there actually miles ahead
of the public sector insurers so it's
something similar to I mean the private
share market gains that we have seen in
the other sectors wherever
private and public are competing be it
Banks Telecom oil and gas now insurance
so anywhere where there is a competition
between private and public it's
generally
private sector which comes out on top
and something similar is playing out
here as well
which is reflected in the growth rates
as well as the market share gains so
this is the sort of overall Story I mean
if you just want to be positive on this
sector then this is the story that
private market share gains now delving
down deeper into the private versus the
public competition
if you look at this plate again right I
mean motor and health is two thirds of
the Market
Within These two health is the fastest
growing segment and it will continue to
be the fastest growing segment in the
future as well
primarily because as I mean people
economically sort of Prosper I mean
first they buy a car then make sure that
they're healthy Etc
is sorry oh I just want to interact once
I don't think we see the next slide we
are still I'm at least I am still seeing
the first slide
oops okay
you're still seeing the first slide or
yes I'm still seeing the first slide
yeah still the first slide
no yeah now we are on the same yeah yeah
is it possible to start a presentation
more I think we can say it a bit broader
yeah it's allows in presentation mode
but can you see the second slide or
still first slide yeah I think I can say
second slide segment split I can see
yeah okay perfect yeah okay yeah so this
is the second slide yeah so uh repeating
myself so motor and health is two thirds
of the market now the growth is
primarily there in the health space
I mean first people buy cars then they
want to sort of Ensure their health and
especially after covet the focuses a lot
more on the health insurance space so
this is where the growth is and this is
where I mean it will sort of make or
break
the insurer who is in this space how big
a market are they able to capture in the
health insurance space
now if you look at the overall Market
ceramic not segment Market set but the
overall market share
so I mean the top five players are
roughly one third of the market these
are private
and I mean even though public is like 40
they're hardly profitable which I'll
come to to a different slide
the top five players have gained a lot
of markets throughout the last 10 years
and if you add star into this because
star is present only in the health space
it will be like close to 45 percent is
owned by these top six players
and they have actually grown their
market share in most cases and most
likely will continue doing so because
the others are not profitable and if
people are following the Reliance Sagar
mentalians had to shut shop because he
was selling at such low prices that
their solventory shows went below the
government mandated numbers
foreign
let me just can you guys see slide three
no it still looks like no students okay
yes yeah yes next one yeah yeah no okay
okay so this is just an overview of
icici's portfolio I mean it would
broadly reflect the market but yeah
motor and health would be the sort of
key areas where they are also having a
large presence
and historically they have grown
around one to one and a half times GDP
growth so these are not strictly
compatible comparable numbers so that
I'm clear I mean they had acquired
bharti AXA so the F5 22 numbers include
the AXA numbers as well
so it's not a pure comparison
but be that as your name because you've
been HDFC had a couple of Acquisitions
they have sort of at least grown by GDP
and in terms of their profitability Etc
it's the sort of biggest player in The
General Insurance Space by profit
by a huge margin and to a lesser extent
in the net earned premium space as well
now if you look at the earnings per
share here I mean there are two ways how
you can actually look at valuing this
company one is people generally look at
the book value per share which is
currently 200 so at whatever 1200 rupees
a share it such six times book
but uh it's been a very long time since
icsa General Insurance actually raised
any money
so it could be argued that it should be
or probably could be valued on a price
to earnings basis as well because the
banks are valid on a Price to Book basis
even though there's an argument that the
business models are similar but sjrc
bank has historically raised money every
five years same with HDFC for icsa
General Insurance till now at least has
not been that case of raising any equity
I think management also has been
confident of maintaining that 15 20
growth rates without diluting any equity
so if we look at it on a price to
earnings basis
then they're probably at 30 times
earnings I think the f523 EPS will
probably be close to 40.
so 20 it's actually yeah
sorry 40 or 30 times earnings which is
probably okay I wouldn't say it's cheap
but it's not that bad as well
now coming uh moving on to the next
slide again let me just close it and
open this again sorry
which is the I mean the main sort of two
ratios that we look at in an insurance
company at least for a general insurance
company is the loss ratio and then lost
ratio plus expense ratio which is the
combined ratio now this is how the
company reports it I mean there are
small differences in the way I have
looked at it in the way company reports
it so FY 22 of course it's pretty
obviously combined ratios were bad
because of the covet crisis
but I mean the loss ratios here which
are around 70 it's broadly been that way
barring the
couple of quarters of kovid it's been
close to that 70 percent mark
now if I look at it on a comparative
basis because on a standalone basis it
does not really
give much information
and just come back to this slide later
on so if we look at the loss ratios
right
now
broadly you could say that ICICI
and Bajaj are in probably the tier one
category I mean they're up there on top
and then I say icis and sorry the ICS up
top HDFC Tata and then probably start
also in the lowest category so that's
because it's purely into hell
so the claims ratios are lowered but
when you look at the chart on the right
the expense ratios for Star are higher
because it's a purely b2c business as
far as possible so the expenses ratios
are higher
slide
you know let me just close my
presentation just open it again now we
see the last ratio next stop sharing
yeah let me just I think this is a
recurring issue let me stop sharing and
share again
if I toggle between screens now can you
see the slides changing
we can see your
um you know you have two screens I think
right what is the presentation yeah
oh yeah I think I'm on my laptop but
I've connected it to my
screen
let me just remove this here so you can
just change it in the display settings
just uh put it on okay yeah on top right
left yeah this past thing duplicate
slideshow you can change good morning
I don't think it's working buttonless
yeah this is perfect now this is fine
right yeah and you can see me switching
between slides yeah perfect perfect okay
okay
so the loss ratios I mean star would
have the lowest loss ratio primarily
because it's a healthy it's only into
health insurance
and the others are higher depending on
the sort of Market they are present in
but the drawback of being purely in
health is that your expense ratios are
also higher
I mean the red one is star so the loss
ratios are the lowest but the expense
ratios are the highest so the combined
ratios would probably also be somewhere
similar to ICICI
and also I mean if you are a multi-line
insurer you automatic risks are spread
out over multiple segments other than
only in one segment
now ICICI where it lost out historically
is in the health space
I mean that's the reason that you see
that the expense ratio for ICICI even
though it was close to 26 or 28
pre-covered it's now close to 34
two reasons primarily one of course the
bhartiya acquisition secondly they have
now finally started focusing more on the
health space
because they've actually lost serious
markets here in the health insurance
space
and just moving I mean the this moving
slide so
10 year or eight years back their health
contribution was around 25 by premium
it's dropped to 22 percent even when
Health has been the fastest growing
space
and you look at their market share
they've lost massive amounts of market
share in the health space
so I think the CEO I think bhargav has
also now realized it I think he's
focusing on the health insurance space
going forward
so this is the sort of play I am also
looking at that I mean once the I mean
agency set up and all the distribution
setup is done for the health insurance
space
this is what should start growing and
currently all the expenses are front
loaded so you do see some bit of eps
compression kicking in because of that
and hopefully over the next two three
years
once I mean the story for health
insurance plays out you will see much
better numbers and you'll see that
actually all others except ICICI they've
actually either maintained or grown
their health market share and if
actually include started I think star is
like one fourth of the health space
so ICICI has lost out on the health
space
and that's the sort of weak point for
ICICI as far as the insurance is
concerned I mean the underwriting is
broadly similar for most players I mean
the loss ratios when there's not much
variability star can be explained
because of the portfolio but broadly
others are all
close to each other between 70 to 75
which is which is fair enough I mean
these two are high over time this should
probably move towards the 70 number then
all of them would be in the 70-75 bucket
and the expense ratio is I mean you
could you would probably aim to have a
combined ratio less than 100 but in the
case of India
the market is still not as stabilized as
in the developed market so it's I mean
the historical numbers have always been
close to 100 percent
but that is fine I think because the
yields in India are also much higher
than in the US in UK so to some extent
even if you are able to
maintain a combined ratio of say 100
percent
and you have a decent investment book
that should sort of ensure that you have
decent Roes
and icic for example is I think guiding
for Roe of 18 it was earlier 20 but now
because of the
I mean expenses for the bharti
acquisition plus the health insurance
increase it's now close to 18 so it's
gone down by two percent because of
these two factors
but at a very very macro level I mean
just moving back to this slide now
so I mean their investment Leverage is
close to 4X so I mean even on a very
worst case basis if they generate only
let's say six percent returns on their
book so that's 24 percent
so that's I mean simply speaking just a
straight 24 re without doing any
underwriting
now if the underwriting is even
semi-decent they should be at least
getting 18 Roes let's assuming they
don't further dilute any equity which
most likely they should not
so at a very macro level if they're able
to just maintain this Forex leverage and
get even six to seven percent returns so
that sort of takes care of their Roes
minus the underwriting numbers
so high level that's the sort of
investment Philosophy for investment
thesis that I have in mind
and secondly the health insurance uh
plays out
now I mean I've not done a comparison
with China in the US Etc because it's
not a surety that each country would
play out the same way
but I had done some comparison with
China a couple of years back so the
health insurance Market in China is
roughly 10x what it is in India
so basically we are where China was 20
years back I mean in terms of the market
size but also uh
health insurance
iteration right because our government
infrastructure Hospital infrastructure
is not the best I would say so having a
private health insurance would uh give
access to Better Health Care for people
right
no I agree I mean
I mean health insurance even life
insurance I mean most insurances are
under penetrated in India so I've I've
not put that set back because that story
is sort of generic for most sectors but
probably even more prevalent for
insurance sector as a whole so that
story is there that it is under
penetrated and it should grow and it has
historically grown as well I think
probably 2x real GDP maybe 1.25 X3
nominal GDP so that that story is there
within this health probably would
provide say three or four x GDP
and your RAM in slow sectors like maybe
fire Marine maybe would be at one
and maybe motor would be at 1.5 but
Health definitely would be at least two
to three x your GDP growth
now the only point is when do these
things turn profitable on a steady state
and stable basis
now I mean last two three years I've
been sort of a washout
so we really can't compare the last two
three years numbers and this whole
sector as a whole I mean it's not yet
mature enough to look at 10-year numbers
and do that sort of analysis so
hopefully in the next 10 years is when
when these things stabilize and we can
sort of look at proper comparison Matrix
I mean going
10 years back Ravi I have more than 10
years
I have a question
uh you know this profitability I think
the way this insurance company report
profitability is completely different
than other sectors because I understand
oh I see Asia and others first 10 15
years they didn't earn any profit
because I think it's it's the way
Insurance regularly has imposed uh
regulations how they report
profitability I couldn't get my head
around it but do you do you know how
they report how what caused them to
report loss for a decade
so there are two P L's actually in in a
general insurance company one is the
shareholders p l and the other is the
policyholders p l so the P and L from
the policyholders flows to the
shareholders p l so I mean as per irda
guidelines you cannot load all the costs
onto the pricing of a policy
so I mean there are some guidelines on
what all costs and what all limits you
are allowed to load onto a policy
so I think I have it open let me just
share that with you I think I was
looking at it let me just uh I think my
question is probably slides in front
right if if I see any take an example
adelvice where I am invested they have
been reporting losses for you know for a
decade now almost right and they say
that they will report it for some more
time and I know ICICI has gone through
hdfs has gone through reporting losses
for a decade and then once they cross
the inflection point then the
profitability comes so what
profitability you see now is could be
just a tip on the iceberg because they
spent decades making sure that they're
all everything is in place before they
report a profit
is that true you have to make upfront
Investments that is true I mean that
assessment I would agree with that you
will not see profitability for a long
time now ICICI has I mean it's beyond
that threshold point it has invested
over the last I think ICC was one of the
first players to get into this space in
2001 so it's been 20 years so they have
a head start just to add to this
discussion like just a quick point which
promote is also making on the chat is uh
we have to differentiate between life
insurers and general insurance and
general insurance is a profitable entity
because the contract uh duration of an
insurance contract is much shorter than
in a life insurance so life insurance
requires much much higher provisioning
or to build up uh loss reserves versus
General Insurance because it rules uh in
one to three at impa General insurance
so icaca Lombard like if even if we go
back in time it has been profitable for
a while now obviously there are certain
upfront costs to set up an insurance
company such as building people process
and whatever but generally life
insurance has has a longer cycle with
versus General insurance and maybe
pramod can also activate because he
works in this sector
so he'll have more insights
and after my limit I mean a lot of
analysts actually do not look at the
profitability numbers for life insurance
companies since like you rightly
mentioned that most of the
profitabilities I mean even in a
long-term contract the profit is
actually the alien of the years of the
contract the initial first few years
were just going paying distributions and
the expenses
so rather than looking at a pack number
which we are doing for a general
insurance company
probably the embedded value would make
more sense for life insurance company
but anyway that's a separate discussion
between life and non-life
but in long life as well I mean
initially you would have X rupees of
expenses and that would be a fixed
expense even having an office or
distribution setup agents Etc
and then that's broadly a fixed cost and
then you start selling in you will have
a J curve of losses and then you'll
begin to the profits but even accounting
for all of that
I mean in the last five years
is the big I mean most of these barring
I say I see I I mean sorry HD sorry
Bajaj have got a good bank Assurance set
up as well
and it's only very recently that I think
ICICI Bank took a call that they would
not actively sort of push all the
products of their insurance subsidies
for both health and not I mean
life and non-life so that was also a bit
of a headwind for ICICI that I mean
suddenly they lost a big share of
premiums from their sort of biggest bank
Assurance partner which is ICICI but I
think long as yes started again slowly
selling some bit of Indemnity policies
Etc
but I mean long term
icsa bank would be the biggest sort of
channel for General Insurance
and they are now trying it looking at
other bank Assurance Partners as well
because I mean end of the day this is a
post product I mean you may think of it
whatever it is I mean motor is a
mandatory insurance so we have to take
it
but I mean unfortunately it is still a
push product I mean people generally
don't want to go and take insurance
without any return at the end
so it's still a push product so the
agency does matter a lot
but hopefully slowly things will change
and people will someone voluntarily look
at
buying your health insurance products
for the after amount you can add them in
your sort of Hands-On view on the sector
rather than a top down View
I think promotes audio is not working so
oh he just commented on a com comment
sir I think that would be the reason
I have like one question which uh like I
I'm wondering if you have thought about
it as to uh now what we see uh in terms
of Roe profile of an ICICI Lombard uh
it's kind of in line with what HDFC bank
has been doing uh kind of 16 to 18 Roe
in the past it used to do 20 plus ROV uh
which has come down and management has
guided uh that it will be in the middle
or High Teens uh for the foreseeable
future because they want to build up
their health insurance uh Venture where
they have lacked significantly
especially on the retail plant
so I I was wondering like why should I
says a Long Bar trade at six times
multiples uh on Book value whereas like
htfc bank for everything is growing at
similar if not higher rates uh versus uh
icac Lumbar and HDFC bank is now at 3.5
times
okay that's I mean good debate because
like I mentioned I think briefly so I
mean you are looking at on a Price to
Book basis which is fair but I'm looking
at it on a price to earnings basis okay
so even on an earnings HDFC bank is like
17 18 times versus
so why should I pay double uh multiple
for something which for which the growth
will be amazed
thing I mean by insurance is probably 20
30 years behind banking in terms of
penetration and the sort of stability
so if you look at HDFC Bank 20 years
back they would have been probably
drilling at similar multiples so you
also need to see where they are in their
space I mean HDFC Bank 20 years back is
probably I mean a very rough back of the
end calculation would be like a
insurance of today because insurance
only got deregulated in 2001 where
private players got
initial five years uh HDFC bank has logo
market share in lending versus icac
Lombard or let's say similar marketing
so it's not like ICC Lombard is a small
company by any stretch of imagination
but you can you should also look at the
profit share I mean so yes maybe premium
shared HDFC ICICI Bajaj there may not be
much difference maybe eight percent
seven percent six percent
but if you look at the profit share
I mean Bajaj and ICICI are like
two-thirds of the private
profit share so it is
even more difficult for them like many
already half of the com half of the
industries profit you're already a big
giant so how much can you get like how
much can you get to because
you you will keep on dominating and you
will keep on growing faster like that's
what hybrid
the other way to look at it is that even
after being in the sector for 20 years I
mean I think everybody would agree that
Bajaj and
I see ICA premium rates are higher than
the other insurance players even if you
compare with the online ones so even
after being in this space for 20 years
and probably charging normal return
rates
they have this profitability which is 18
Ro East now the others are definitely
undercutting that's why they are not the
same sort of profitability as the
icici's and Bajaj is so the other ways
either ICICI goes down to 15 Roe and
takes market share or the other ways the
others need to increase their pricing if
they need to get better Roes now we'll
need to see how it actually plays out
but I mean Beyond a point even say any
needle wise or SBI Tata star Etc they
shareholders would also want to see some
profits or some Roes at the end of the
day you will you will put losses for
okay 10 years that's fine I mean
everybody is everybody understands that
you will have a long sort of period
before you are profitable
but that you also need to look at it in
the context that money was available
cheaply for a long period of time today
that is not the case no I don't know
whether it will be the same diffusion or
not but today that's not the case so you
would need to have some profitability
so if the others I mean let's evaluate
both the scenarios let's assume that the
other competitors increase their pricing
to be able to get normal profitability
in which case then you will not really
be able to differentiate between icsa
Bajaj or let's say needle wise or a star
for example in terms of a customer
wanting to buy any of these policies
right now I mean most people would opt
for the cheapest auto insurance policy
but that's because the others are not
maintaining decent rovs if they increase
their pricing then maybe people will
pick an ICICI over let's say tata for
example
now the other scenario is that okay
the other players don't reduce
their pricing they stay where they are
which is what is happening and that's
why you'll see that ICICI is getting
more active in the health space because
they've realized that by sort of
maintaining their premiums they have not
gained any market share
and that also explains the two percent
lower guidance is that they need to now
pay up to set up their health insurance
space so it's possible that the 18 goes
to 17 16 15 that's possible
but the Headway sorry the runway for
growth I would say at least 20 years I
mean you have that visibility for some
terminal growth
whereas for a lot of the other sectors
that itself is not visible
and I I mean I mean HDFC ban for a long
time was trading at five six times Price
to Book
so a six year six there is actually a
six in ICICI is actually cheaper than a
six in HDFC because an HDFC was diluting
money every five years whereas ICICI has
not diluted that equity
so I mean to be in Apple's travels
probably six is comparable to a 9 in
HDFC I mean I'm just making up numbers
but the point is to show that the
dilution of equity is not captured in
that six
one more thing you said the combined
ratio of hundred
right so does that mean that they don't
generate any money on their you know
underwriting all their so he's pretty
much a bait on their float and their
investment track record
that's that's probably a good way to put
it is as of now yes because I mean with
combined ratios of 100 they're really
not making any money underwriting
and it's as of now it's basically a
float game I mean they're making money
only on account of float if you remove
the float income from their pnls I mean
they're all in losses
and this is that important thing to look
at is because
since their combined ratios are above
100 the additional float that they will
generate is mostly just Returns on their
investment because
there's not much sort of free cash flow
left after underwriting
okay well that's yeah that's a good one
yeah thank you
and which is the most profitable in for
underwriting in in the peer group
so now if you look at the loss ratio
right which is the sort of comparison
so I mean you need to exclude star
because it's only into health
so I mean if you think if you divide the
sort of four segments into
sort of long tail short tail right I
mean see fire Marine most insurance
company would in I mean opt for
reinsurance because there are like long
tail events I mean if something one
catastrophe can sort of have wide
impacts so most of it
I mean any sensible insurance company
would look at reinsuring
it is motor and health which are like
smaller claims and typically I mean I
mean I know it's not a good example now
because covert happened but it's not
going to happen then suddenly 20 people
die or you have 20 accidents of your
policies in a year I mean these are more
like normal curve distributions where I
mean broadly these things are similar
year to year excluding kovid it doesn't
like I said the example is not very
valid because of covet but broadly we
have stable businesses so insurance
companies would want to retain a large
chunk of the premium for motor and
health
and again in health it again depends
whether it's it's a group or a retail
policy now retail
policy
you would have say lower loss ratios
which is fair which is why star you see
is the loss ratios are over here
but then you need to spend a lot of
money to get this retail health
insurance book
whereas for a group policy I mean your
loss ratios would be like 95 or 98 but
you don't have that expense ratio
so it's a combination of both I mean
it's not a simple answer that if you
only do Health retail you are better off
or if you do only do Health Group you're
better off so you need to have a mix of
both
and I see I see I sort of lost out on
the retail Health space which is why
they are struggling here and now I mean
they are sort of very late to the party
you can just see the amount of money
they're having they're having to spend
just to play catch up
good broadly if you exclude those
differences
I mean I mean they're broadly all the
same I mean I wouldn't really say that
somebody is a far woman better
underwriter than the others I mean
they're all all around the same numbers
I mean this is probably just because
they are newer than icse and Bajaj
but eventually they'll also all
sort of all converge in that 70 75
percent ratio bucket
thank you thank you that's why the idea
is not gone for IPO as well they know
that they are still not there
in terms of stability once they are
stable they'll definitely do an IPO